<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drive Today</title>
    <description>All things driving, reviews and great content.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:13:20 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:13:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Audi Q2 S-line, the hatchback disguised as an SUV</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Price: £27,060&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body Style: SUV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuel Type: Diesel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engine Size: 1598cc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHP: 114 BHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top Speed: 122 MPH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0-60 MPH: 10.50 Secs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting vehicle to drive, it was a very high ride compared to the likes of the A-Class and A3, however, it handled just the same while also taking no more space when parking the vehicle in tight spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The size of the vehicle was lacking when it came to the interior. It shouts SUV when it comes to the look and feels but unfortunately lacks when it comes to size and capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s unclear what the intended use of this vehicle is. It looks like a quality vehicle that is trying to enter the SUV world but just not quite living up to the other vehicles in its range such as the Q3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who is this vehicle for, it is unclear, but my take on it would be those who like compact sporty looking (not quite) SUVs and aren’t bothered about space and capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/audi/q2/exterior-back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Audi Q2 Exterior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audi Q2 is a very stylish vehicle both on the inside and out. It has very slick lines going the length of the vehicle. What wasn’t so nice was the basic A3 interior which always feels like it is lacking something. The gear stick does have a premium feel to it though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/audi/q2/interior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Audi Q2 Interior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was still very stylish and extremely well built for something near to an entry-level model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive was nice. It isn’t the quickest car about although it can be nippy at low speeds. The handling was also nice and smooth when cornering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it is a pleasant car. It looks nice and sporty, has a good ride height and establishes you on the road. However, it is a lot of money for something that isn’t quite as spacious as it looks. For the price tag, this comes as I’m not sure this would be the first choice for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/audi-q2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/audi-q2/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        <category>SUV</category>
        
        <category>Premium</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mercedez-benz A-Class AMG Line</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Price: £27,095&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For such a small car, it makes a statement. The fact it is the premium trim adds to the impact it makes on the road. The front grill is quite possibly the cars most defining feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the entire car is pleasant to look at, it can become dull towards the back of the vehicle. It seems all the work has been put into making the front so special that the rear is lacking some care and attention, that being said it does not have a negative impact on the car in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This car is for those who don’t need anything particularly large but still want a nice and slick looking car. It isn’t particularly fast even when going into the large engine sizes so bear that in mind if you want something nippy, other than that you can’t go wrong with the Mercedez A-Class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the styling of this vehicle is second to none, it has a stance that will leave a statement where ever you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grill is the defining feature of the A-Class, it has a premium feel to the grill. There are two major designs the metal bars which drop vertically and the black diamond feature which spans across the entire grill. Unfortunately, it starts to lose its exploding design further backwards you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interior of the car follows nicely from what you see of the outside with the sleek centre console straight out of a high-end model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gear leaver isn’t in your typical location and instead on the steering wheel tidying up the space in the centre. Instead, you have a nice leather handrest which also allows greater control of the user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do happen to be taking corners at any sort of speed then the bucket seats will give you a really snug feel, they are all leather with a nice and tight fit making sure you know you’re ready to take any corner thrown at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is a slow vehicle, it feels stable and comfortable when accelerating. The engine is also nice and quiet when moving at higher speeds. When travelling at 70mph along the motorway then you will be happy to travel long distances, particularly with the diesel engine, providing extremely good miles per gallon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap it up, this is a wonderful car, it will get you from A to B in comfort and without using too much fuel. Also, don’t expect to get to that place quickly, but at least you’ll enjoy getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The space offered is lacking ever so slightly so if you are going to be carrying 4-5 people in the car regularly then maybe look for something larger such as the B-Class or C-Class. If I was looking for a small to medium car for under £30,000, this would be near, if not, at the top of the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/mercedez-benz-a-class/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mercedez-benz-a-class/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        <category>Hatchback</category>
        
        <category>Premium</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Skoda Octavia Estate</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Price: £21,105&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body Style: Estate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuel Type: Petrol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engine Size: 1498cc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHP: 147 BHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top Speed: 133 MPH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0-60 MPH: 8.4 Secs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skoda Octavia estates most impressive feature has got to be the uncompromising space that it comes with. There is enough space in there to cater for adventurous be it camping, golfing, skiing, or even a trip down to the DIY store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The space this car provides will be appealing to anyone who uses their car for more than just commuting and weekly shop. As mentioned above, the boot size alone can accommodate a variety of different scenarios such as an airport run with the family in the car. With the seats down the capacity becomes extremely accomodating and will fit a decent sized snowboard and a couple of mountain bikes. This car is definitely about space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is not the most beautiful car on the market, however, that being said the recent work Skoda has done with the grill and the lines down the side of the vehicle has modernised the design. It certainly does not feel dated and likely will not for many years. There is not much else to point out about the exterior other than it being a reasonable mid-range car. A possible improvement could be to the wheels, they are very standard for the standard edition. For an SE model, it is a reasonable looking car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What jumps out the most about the interior is the centre console, it comes with a reasonably large touch screen with an impressively easy user interface. The gear stick is also quite impressive with a nice robust gear change. Where it starts to lack in quality is the seats, the fabric lacks a soft touch. That being said about the quality of the seats, they are large and accomodating which is comfortable on long-distance drives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a 1.5 litre the car can be quite nippy, this feels like it is down to the transmission, gear changes are very smooth and seamless. Driving along the motorway at 70mph feels comfortable with little cabin noise and has a sturdy feel, gripping to the road. Handling can be clunky at times, especially navigating in tight spaces. Finally moving onto the fuel economy, it is reasonable for such a large vehicle and averaged out about 40mpg in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the Skoda Octavia estate was a very reasonable car for the price range it is in. The cabin experience felt nice and contemporary. Fixtures such as the door handles and armrest could improve. Space is fantastic and a very good car for the money. If I required an entry-level car with a lot of space I would certainly consider this car.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/skoda-octavia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/skoda-octavia/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        <category>Estate</category>
        
        <category>Standard</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Volvo XC60 Inscription Pro, the mid-level premium SUV</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Price: £43,400&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body Style: SUV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuel Type: Electric Diesel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engine Size: 1969cc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHP: 232 BHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top Speed: 112 MPH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0-60 MPH: 7.1 Secs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving the top of the range model Volvo XC60 Inscription Pro was an absolute pleasure. The driving position gave a sense of control on the road. A high driving position mixed with the ergonomic design Volvo engineers for all their seats gives you a sense of stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The car is large in size yet the power steering makes you forget you are in control of such a large vehicle. The fact that is also all-wheel drive means that you feel the car moves together as a whole unit and even kicks the front up a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the components of the vehicle feel as though they have been individually handcrafted for each car from the steering wheel to the handles on the doors. On this specific model, the gear stick has a crystal-like design which carries a sense of luxury and adds to the premium feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/volvo/xc60/interior.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Volvo XC60 Interior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large and heavy vehicles can sometimes come with a much louder cockpit noise level, this is negated in here. While there is still some noise, Volvo has done a good job in insulating it to reduce wind noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performance of the XC60 was impressive, its 2.0-litre and boasts an impressive 232 BHP from it’s Swedish engineered engine. What was surprising was the fuel economy, it seemed to sip the fuel and took the fuel gauge some time to show any change. This is great to see on a medium-size SUV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving this vehicle was done in adverse weather conditions so I got to see how it handled in extremely wet and windy conditions. As mentioned earlier, this is an all-wheel-drive so there were no issues with handling on potentially hazardous corners. Motorway driving was a breeze, keeping its position in the lane with ease despite strong winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto one of the core reasons someone may decide to drive an SUV, the size. The amount of space throughout the car was fantastic, from the passenger space to the boot capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/volvo-xc60/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/volvo-xc60/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        <category>SUV</category>
        
        <category>Premium</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mini Cooper S Sport Hatch is a dream sunday driver</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Price: £24,580&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Body Style: Hatchback&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fuel Type: Petrol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engine Size: 1998cc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BHP: 189 BHP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Top Speed: 146 MPH&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0-60 MPH: 6.70 Secs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with a quick breakdown of the entire driving experience. The vehicle was driven over 3 days, around 400 miles and a total of £60 in fuel. Throughout the test drive, I took the car on a variety of different roads to see how it well it performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I found during the test drive was it felt most at home on country roads. While on country roads it just kept on giving, the power and torque outputted from the engine are quite engaging. The steering is heavy making it feel more precise and comfortable when tackling what the Formby roads had to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that it is so nippy made cornering much more fun as you do not have to worry about getting back up to speed when on bendy roads. The sound that came from the engine when the turbo is engaged became highly addictive and I frequently wound the window down in the cold autumn weather just to hear the whine from the engine every time I set off from the lights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where it didn’t feel so comfortable was driving along the motorway. When I reached 70 miles per hour, the Mini feel a little uneasy and unsteady. The sound from inside was quite loud and overpowered the stereo at a moderate volume. It is safe to say, if you are going to be doing plenty of long-distance motorway driving, then this might not be the car for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The practicality of the vehicle is questionable. It is lacking in space and storage right across the vehicle. While driving the Mini I decided to test the space available by attempting to do some shopping. At this point, I realised the large bag of Christmas presents did not fit in the boot (if you can call it that) and I had to drop the rear seats to fit everything in the car. It did, however, handle the weekly shop comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While on the point of practicality I want to point out that while this is a “5 seat” vehicle, you would be lucky to fit anyone in the back of the two-door hatch. They build this car for two people and no more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line is, the Cooper is a bundle of fun, nippy and exciting to drive. Unfortunately, it is a pretty impractical car for everyday use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I highly approve of the Mini Cooper S, it is extremely enjoyable and put and smile on my face and keep it there the entire time that I was behind the wheel. Although this may not be the most practical car particularly for carrying large loads, it is certainly a fun car and will make a fantastic Sunday driver.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/mini-cooper-s-sport-hatch/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/mini-cooper-s-sport-hatch/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        <category>Hatchback</category>
        
        <category>Premium</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BMW 3 Series is an all-round great car</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The BMW 3 series that is being reviewed is a 2-litre unleaded saloon E90 model, for those who are unsure this is the model in production between 2004-2013, this one is a 2010 model. It was driven as a long term every day driver and was operated in a variety of different conditions and environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting fact about driving the 3 series is that it offers a great deal in both practicality and enjoyment. It is a large car with 5 seats and can comfortably accommodate for all of them seats to be occupied. The boot is large and has a wide opening so that it is easy to access anything stored in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be stated that like all BMW vehicles, this is a rear wheel drive. If you have not driven a rear wheel vehicle before then you will certainly notice the different when driving a BMW 3 series, especially when it comes to cornering the vehicle at high speeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where you may find yourself driving along at a steady speed you may not want to put your foot down on the gas pedal otherwise you might find the rear end twitching a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On country roads the car could find its way around corners without any issues and still find the power to get back up to speed without too much hassle. Where the 3 series is really in its prime is motorway driving and you’re A-roads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The large build of the car made it steady and comfortable when travelling along at high speeds. It is also quite in the cockpit when driving along the motorway at 70 miles per hour and found itself staying comfortably within its lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the E90 3 series came without a console screen, for many people that may be considered a negative factor when deciding if they wanted to own and drive a car. For me it was a blessing, it was less of a distraction and when night driving it became much more engaging not having a distractive bright screen lighting up the entire interior. I was able to focus more on the road ahead and became more immersed in the driving experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/bmw-3-series-e90/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/bmw-3-series-e90/</guid>
        
        <category>Drive</category>
        
        
        <category>Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
